

Email: xinyu.shi@uwaterloo.ca

RESEARCH INTEREST

My current research focuses on **Human-Computer Interaction**, particularly, **Human-AI Co-Creation** and **AI-Powered Creativity Support Tool**. The goal of my research is to design, develop, and evaluate interactive AI systems that effectively incorporate human intent into the computation process in order to boost the productivity of creative activities. My research seeks to gain a deeper understanding of the flow of creativity and to enhance human intelligence and creativity.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Computer Science | advisor: Prof. Jian Zhao

University of Waterloo

Waterloo, ON, Canada

Website: https://xinyu-shi.github.io/

**B.Eng.** in Software Engineering

Sept. 2016 – Jun. 2020 Xiamen, China

Sept. 2021 – Present

Xiamen University

### **PUBLICATIONS**

## C.1 De-Stijl: Facilitating Graphics Design with Interactive 2D Color Palette Recommendation

X. Shi, Z. Zhou, J. Zhang, A. Neshati, A. K. Tyagi, R. Rossi, S. Guo, F. Du, and J. Zhao. Conditionally accepted by ACM CHI 2023.

## C.2 Real-World Blind Super-Resolution via Feature Matching with Implicit High-Resolution Priors

C. Chen\*, X. Shi\*, Y. Qin, X. Li, X. Han, T. Yang, and S. Guo. (\* equal contribution)

In Proceedings of the 30th ACM International Conference on Multimedia (MM2022). Oral (Top 5%)

## C.3 Teaching American Sign Language in Mixed Reality

Q. Shao, A. Sniffen, J. Blanchet, M. E. Hillis, X. Shi, T. K. Haris, J. Liu, J. Lamberton, M. Malzkuhn, L. C.

Quandt, J. Mahoney, D. Kraemer, X. Zhou, and D. Balkcom.

In Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT, Ubicomp2021).

#### C.4 Accurate and Fast Classification of Foot Gestures for Virtual Locomotion

X. Shi\*, J. Pan\*, Z. Hu, J. Lin, S. Guo, M. Liao, Y. Pan, and L. Liu. (\* equal contribution)

In Proceedings of the 2019 IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality (ISMAR2019).

## J.1 Droplet-Transmitted Infection Risk Ranking Based on Close Proximity Interaction

S. Guo, J. Yu, X. Shi, H. Wang, F. Xie, X. Gao, and M. Jiang.

Frontiers in Neurorobotics 13 (2020): 113.

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Waterloo	Waterloo, ON, Canada
------------------------	----------------------

Graduate Research Assistant in HCI | Advised by Prof. Jian Zhao

Sept. 2021 – Present

Design interactive Human-AI Co-Creation system to augment human creativity and productivity.

### The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Shenzhen

Research Assistant in CV | Advised by Prof. Xiaoguang Han

Dec. 2020 - Aug. 2021

Shenzhen, China

Proposed an approach based on Vector-Quantized GAN for Image Super-Resolution.

### Dartmouth College Hanover, NH, USA

Research Assistant in HCI | Advised by Prof. Xia Zhou and Prof. Xing-Dong Yang

Sept. 2019 – Apr. 2020

Leveraged wearable sensing technique and Mixed-Reality to facilitate American-Sign-Language teaching.

# Xiamen University Xiamen, China

Research Assistant in HCI | Advised by Prof. Shihui Guo

Sept. 2017 - Aug. 2021

Exploited wearable devices, i.e., smart insoles, for VR locomotion with learned gesture recognition models.

# HONORS AND AWARDS

Vector Scholarship in AI, Vector Institute   \$17,500 for one year	2021
International Doctoral Student Award, University of Waterloo   \$15,000 per year	2021
Award for Excellence in Academic Performance, Xiamen University   ¥5,000 per year	2017 - 2020

#### SKILLS

**Programming**: Python, C, C++, Java, SQL, Shell **Framework**: PyTorch, D3.js, Numpy, Sklearn